<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="hdr_mastering_metadata_unstable_v1">

  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2019 Intel

    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
    copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
    to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
    the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
    and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
    Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including the next
    paragraph) shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the
    Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
    IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
    FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT.  IN NO EVENT SHALL
    THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
    LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
    FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER
    DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <description summary="hdr mastering meta data protocol">
    This protocol provides the ability to specify the mastering color volume
    metadata for an HDR video, for a given surface.
    These values give an idea of the brightness of the video, which can be
    used by the display so that it can adjust itself for a better viewing
    experience.

    The hdr-metadata values are enocoded in the video and the client can
    retreive these values and provide them to the compositor.

    A client need to first get the color-space interface for the HDR
    color-space using the color-manager protocol, via ICC profile.
    Then it needs to get the hdr_mastering_surface using
    hdr_mastering_metadata interface. The get_hdr_surface(), provides the
    hdr_surface interface which can be used to set the hdr mastering meta-data.
  </description>

  <interface name="zwp_hdr_mastering_metadata_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="hdr mastering metadata">
      The hdr matering metadata is a singleton global object that provides
      the extenstion hdr_surface for a given surface.
    </description>

    <enum summary="error">
      <entry name="hdr_surface_exists" value="0"
	      summary="The hdr surface exists for given surface."/>
    </enum>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the hdr_mastering_metadata object">
        Destroy the HDR mastering metadata object.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="get_hdr_surface">
      <description summary="get the interface for hdr_surface">
        This interface is created for a surface and the hdr mastering metadata
	should be attached to this surface.
      </description>
      <arg name="hdr_surface" type="new_id" interface="zwp_hdr_surface_v1"/>
      <arg name="surface" type="object" interface="wl_surface"/>
    </request>

  </interface>

  <interface name="zwp_hdr_surface_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="an interface to add hdr mastering metadata">
      An interface to add the hdr mastering metadata like MAX-CLL and MAX-FALL,
      for a given surface.
    </description>

    <request name="set_hdr_mastering_metadata">
      <description summary="set the hdr mastering metadata for the surface.">
        This request is double buffered and it will be applied to the surface
	on wl_surface::commit.
      </description>
      <arg name="max_cll" type="uint" summary="MAX Content Light Level"/>
      <arg name="max_fall" type="uint" summary="MAX Frame Average Light Level"/>
      <arg name="max_lum" type="uint" summary="MAX Luminance"/>
      <arg name="min_lum" type="uint" summary="MIN Luminance"/>
    </request>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the hdr mastering surface object">
        Destroy the hdr_surface.
      </description>
    </request>
  </interface>
</protocol>
